Muhammad Burhan Ahmad

Dubai, UAE

E: <u>muhdburh@gmail.com</u> **M:** +971521566568

www.linkedin.com/in/burhan066 https://burhanahmad02.github.io/

PROFILE

As a passionate game developer with over two years of experience, I have developed and deployed more than 10 games. I have worked with teams of up to 15 people, managing all aspects of the game development process, from concept to launch. With a strong background in programming, design, and project management, I am committed to creating engaging and immersive game experiences that captivate players. I am eager to continue advancing my knowledge of AI algorithms and their application in game development, with a goal of achieving even greater success in the gaming industry.

EDUCATION

Comsats University Islamabad, Pakistan

BSc Computer Science

2017-2021

TECH SKILLS & PROJECTS

Skills: Unity 3D, C#, Trello, Slack, Source Control, Doxygen

Artificial Intelligence: Computer Vision, Image Processing, Pattern recognition, Machine learning, Image Labelling, Testing, Creating Datasets

Soft-Skills: Leadership, Team-management, Collaborative, Cooperative, Analytical thinking, Team Player

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Game Ever Studio Pvt. Ltd Dubai, UAE Unity Game Developer

April 2022 - Present

Five Ocean 2D

- Implemented mechanics and physics-based Submarine, resulting in a more realistic and engaging gameplay experience
- Developed an Al manager that spawns and assigns random enemies with unique patrol routes in water, and increases their abilities over time, including accuracy in detecting the player. The enemies shoot the player if detected nearby
- Coded a Radar System which was responsible for detecting enemies with each clockwise rotation of its sweep, resulting in a 30% increase in player engagement
- Built an AI system to help players locate hidden enemies in a game, demonstrating expertise in both game design and programming

FPS Game

- Crafted seamless, immersive gameplay by expertly designing a unique First-Person character, controller, and challenging, reactive Enemy AI system. Translated complex game concepts into engaging experiences
- Overall UI implementation and UI animation

• FPS Sci-fi Game

- Built immersive, visually stunning effects for environments and weapons using particle effects (VFX), sound effects, and shader programming, demonstrating an exceptional ability to combine technical skills with artistic flair
- Crafted dynamic, captivating death animations for the player using Cine-machine virtual camera, showcasing a deep understanding of both animation and programming

- Boosted game performance by compressing sound and sprite sizes, creating a faster, seamless player experience. Demonstrated attention to detail and optimization
- Introduced an innovative, scalable Achievement system using scriptable objects, streamlining the development process and creating an engaging, rewarding player experience, highlighting a rare combination of creativity and technical expertise

Sniper 3D FPS Game

- Devised and developed an Upgrade system for the attachments of the sniper rifles
- Target shooting level, where player can practice their aim and accuracy

Viral Mobi Tech Pvt. Ltd Islamabad, Pakistan Game Developer Jan 2022 – April 2022

Draw Bridge 2D

- Established mechanics and physics-based vehicle
- Utilized line renderer to draw a path with colliders and physics

Spartans Global Pvt. Ltd Islamabad, Pakistan Game Dev Trainee Dec 2020 – Dec 2021

- Santa Pin-pull 2D SGPL Games
 - Leveraged Addressable for optimization of memory for 120 levels
 - Diversified the purchasable and rewarded gifts in the Shop by implementing JSON

• Rush To Crush - SGPL Games Unity Game Developer

- Enacted a bike based on mechanics, physics, and 2D ragdoll physics
- Setup architecture to shift to scriptable objects
- Introduced a shared biker rig, for custom animation

Fashion Makeover - SGPL Games Unity Game Developer

- Designed and implemented architecture using scriptable objects
- Optimized addressable implementation for scalable item database
- Collaborated and guided Art and Design teams to ensure the best visuals and performance
- Co-ordinated all core game mechanics

Potato Knights Pvt. Ltd Islamabad, Pakistan Intern (Game Dev) Jan 2020 – April 2020 EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES & AWARDS

Awards:

• Fast University (Nuces):

Nascon-18 participated in Dota2, Nascon-18 participated in FIFA, Nascon-17 participated in Tekken-7 - Fast University

• University of Engineering and Technology:

- Tech-salvo 18 winner for Dota2 UET
- Comecs-18 runner up for Call of duty 4 Comsats University Islamabad

Community meetups:

- Attended a One-day workshop on soft skills and Personality Development in Comsats University Islamabad
- Attended a One-day workshop on Linked-In in Comsats University Islamabad
- Attended a One-day workshop on C# programming skills in Comsats University Islamabad